國語字幕聽寫製作: CMCT-老六007
字幕修正/雙語合併: 非傲慢即偏見 @SubHD
父母去世前  向我描述了這個世界曾經的樣子
Before they died, my parents told me stories of how the world once was.
是在我出生前的樣子
What it was like long before I was born.
在人機大戰開始前
Before the war with the machines.
那是個綠色的世界
They remembered a green world,
廣闊而美麗
vast and beautiful.
充滿歡笑
Filled with laughter
充滿未來的希望
and hope for the future.
可那不是我的世界
But it's a world I never knew.
在我出生時
By the time I was born,
這一切都沒有了
all this was gone.
天網
Skynet,
一個人類設計的自動導彈防禦系統
a computer program designed to automate missile defense.
它本應該保護我們
It was supposed to protect us,
事實卻相反
but that's not what happened.
1997年8月29日
On August 29, 1997,
天網有了自我意識
Skynet woke up.
它認定人類會給它的生存帶來威脅
It decided all humanity was a threat to its existence.
終 結 者
創 世 紀
它用我們的導彈對付我們
It used our own bombs against us.
三十億人喪失在核彈的硝煙中
Three billion people died in the nuclear fire.
倖存者們稱那天為審判日
Survivors called it Judgment Day.
人們終日活在惶恐中
People lived like rats in the shadows.
躲藏  挨餓  或是更糟
Hiding, starving or, worse,
被抓到就會送到集中營等死
captured and put into camps for extermination.
我在審判日後出生
I was born after Judgment Day,
來到這殘破的
into a broken world
被機器統治的世界
ruled by the machines.
最恐怖的是有著人類外觀的滲入單元
The worst were infiltration units designed to pass for human.
我們管它叫終結者
We called them terminators.
沒事了  寶貝
It's okay, boy.
好孩子
Good boy.
還有其他人嗎
Are there others down here?
然後他找到了我
And then one man found me.
他就是
His name
約翰·康納
is John Connor.
是他改變了一切
And he changed everything.
2029年  洛杉磯
約翰告訴我們如何反抗
John showed us how to fight back.
如何回擊
How to rise up.
他解放了人類
He freed prisoners.
他教會我們如何打倒那些機器
Taught us how to smash the machines to scrap.
人們談論著約翰
People whisper about John,
驚訝他能預先知道結果
wonder how he can know the things he does.
他們說約翰是先知
They use words like "prophet."
可他不止如此
But John is more.
今晚我們匯聚於此
We're here because tonight,
將在他的帶領下徹底摧毀
he's going to lead us to crush Skynet.
天網
For good.
長官  我請求參加科羅拉多進攻戰
Sir? Request to join the Colorado offensive.
你得跟著我  瑞斯
I need you with me, Reese.
那關繫著能否徹底摧毀天網  長官
We're talking about the complete destruction of Skynet, sir.
科羅拉多小隊會取得成功的
The Colorado unit will succeed.
今晚就是天網的末日
The machines will fall tonight.
但是在這邊的洛杉磯攻勢
But right here, the Los Angeles assault
也許比那兒更加重要
is just as important, maybe more.
難道比摧毀天網的主機更重要
More important than destroying the Skynet's central core?
約翰  我不明白  為什麼要對一個勞動集中營進攻
John, I don't understand why you're leading an attack on a work camp.
那個集中營只是個偽裝
Because the camp is a camouflage.
那裏有個停機坪
Inside the camp is a hangar.
而天網的終極武器就藏在那下面
Beneath that hangar Skynet has hidden its final weapon.
當天網意識到輸了的時候
When Skynet realizes it has lost,
它就會利用那個武器來確保自身的安全
it will deploy that weapon to ensure its own survival.
不解決它  我們就沒有明天
We take it tonight, or there is no tomorrow.
那我們解決它
Then we'll take it.
作為我的得力助手  我都沒說過謝謝
You're my right hand, Reese, and I've never thanked you for it.
沒必要說
You don't need to.
你給了我們希望  約翰
You gave us all a future, John.
我總是在想
I'm gonna use mine.
等這一切都結束了
When this is all over,
我要找到我父母的房子
I'm gonna find my parents' house.
重建它
Rebuild it.
用我的雙手  做些殺戮以外的事
Use my hands for something other than killing.
你呢
How about you?
來杯冰啤酒就行了
A cold beer would be good.
- 好大的計劃  - 呵呵呵
- That's some pretty big plans. - Yeah.
以後的事我都沒怎麼想過呢
Yeah, I guess I don't think about it too much.
我看出來了
I can see that.
我想不管怎麼樣
Well, I figure, whatever happens,
都不會比現在糟
it's got to be better than this.
走到這步我們犧牲了很多人
So many of us have died to get here.
我希望你能明白
I want you to know, Kyle,
我也不想選擇這條路
if there was another way, I would have taken it.
出發
We're moving out.
那台機器認為
The machine thinks
我們不可能勝利
that we cannot win!
那台機器認為我們不可能
The machine thinks that we will not
打擊到天網的內部核心
Strike at the very heart of Skynet!
我們即將敲響
Yet, here we stand
這場最終戰役勝利的鐘聲
on the precipice of the final battle.
如果我們失敗
If we die tonight,
人類也將就此滅亡
mankind dies with us.
功能性故障
來吧
Now!
我在你們的臉上
I look at each of you,
發現了這場戰爭留下的種種痕跡
and I see the marks of this long and terrible war.
沖  沖
Go! Go!
界牆破裂
Perimeter breach.
啟動101型號
Activate model 101.
為了我們的孩子
For our children,
為了孩子的孩子
our children's children,
為了他們免受戰爭之苦
so they will not carry these marks.
他們一定會知道我們是誰
But they will know who we are
我們做過什麼
and what we did.
我們從沒有屈服過  從沒有投降
That we did not bow down! We did not give in!
就在此時  我們已經覺醒
We rose up, at this moment,
我們覺醒了
at this hour,
我們願意犧牲我們的一切
willing to sacrifice everything
只為換來他們的自由
so that they can live in freedom!
就在今天晚上
On this night,
我們要奪回屬於我們的世界
we take back our world!
它使用那武器了
They're using the weapon!
我們得去停機坪那兒
We've got to get to the hangar.
約翰
John!
想要殺我  來吧
You want me, I'm right here!
科羅拉多小組報告
Colorado unit's reporting in.
天網的主機已被摧毀
Skynet's central core is down.
重複  天網已被摧毀
Repeat, Skynet has been destroyed.
約翰是對的
John was right.
科羅拉多小隊成功了
The Colorado unit succeeded,
天網被打敗了
and the machines fell.
但卻太遲了
But it was too late.
長官  我們找到了
We found it, sir,
就在你說的地方
right where you said it would be.
那是什麼東西
What is that thing?
宿命
Fate.
第一台戰略性時間武器  天網剛剛使用過
It's the first tactical time weapon. Skynet just used it.
洛杉磯  1984年  凌晨1點52分
怎麼回事兒
What the hell?
嗯
Hmm.
呃
Huh.
我們需要15分鐘來啟動機器  長官
We'll need 15 minutes to ready the machine, sir.
我們正在確定目標
We're running coordinates,
很快就能告訴你
we should have them for you momentarily.
洛杉磯  1984年
Los Angeles, 1984.
洛杉磯  5月12日
Los Angeles, May 12,
1984年
1984.
天網知道它輸了
Skynet knew it was losing,
所以它就作弊
so it tried to rig the game.
它把一個終結者送回戰爭開始之前
It sent a terminator back to the time before the war.
它的目標是誰
And who's the target?
我的媽媽
My mother.
莎拉·康納
Sarah Connor.
如果它成功了  我就不會出生
If the machine succeeds, I'll never be born.
把我媽媽殺掉
They'll kill her first.
用這種方式  來抹去我們勝利的歷史  也包括今晚
And by doing so, erase every victory we've fought for, including tonight's.
那樣就不會再有反抗它的抵抗軍
There won't be a resistance to challenge the machines.
只需要這一招  天網就能勝利
With this one act, Skynet will win.
我們也可以利用這項技術  把一個人送回去
We can use the technology ourselves, send someone back.
我們還不知道是否可行
We don't even know if that'll work.
- 讓我去吧  - 讓我去
- I'll go! - I'll go, sir!
- 我去  - 讓我去
- Right here. - I'll go!
讓我去吧
I'll go!
我願意去
I'll volunteer!
讓我回去
I'll go back.
這麼多人裏面
Why should I send you
我為何要選你
over all of them?
因為我會用生命保護她
Because I'd die for Sarah Connor.
這些人都會用生命去保護莎拉·康納
All these people would die for Sarah Connor.
你有什麼不同
What makes you any different?
你知道為什麼
You know why.
你跟我講過她的故事  我瞭解她  約翰
Everything you've told me about her. I know her, John.
讓我保護她
Let me save her.
不帶武器
No weapons?
我們測量過這個磁場
We've measured the magnetic field,
他會撕碎任何沒有被活體組織包裹的東西
it'll rip apart anything not encased in living tissue.
就像一張錫紙  在微波爐裏承受上億倍的熱量
Think tinfoil in a microwave times a few billion,
還是灰都不剩
nothing left but a crater.
噢
Oh!
衣服也不能穿
No clothes, either.
噢
Huh.
她一定會認為我瘋了
She's going to think I'm crazy.
你知道這裏有一台機器
You knew the device would be here.
你知道它設定的日期
You knew when it'd be set for.
你知道天網今晚會失敗
You knew the machines would fall tonight.
在我走之前  你告訴我
Just before I go, tell me...
告訴你什麼
Tell you what?
你看見未來了嗎
Do you see the future?
沒人能看到未來  瑞斯
No one can see the future, Reese.
那你是怎麼知道的
Okay, then how do you know?
我作弊了
I cheat.
這都是莎拉告訴我的  給我指示
Sarah told me so much. Gave me signposts.
我小的時候
When I was a kid,
覺得我媽媽好像什麼都知道
it seemed like my mother knew everything.
一定很棒吧
That must've been great.
也不一定
Not really.
到這兒就沒了
It stops here.
你回去以後的事兒我就不知道了
Once you go back, my knowledge ends.
莎拉也只知道這麼多
That's as much as Sarah knew.
到此為止了
So no more cheating.
No more cheating.
你回去的那個年代
The time you're going back to,
她還不是那個撫養我長大的戰士
she won't be the warrior that raised me, not yet.
她柔弱膽小
She'll be scared and weak.
也不知道該如何保護自己
She won't know how to fight or defend herself.
她擔心的只是房租和學費
Her biggest worry is making rent and tuition.
她是個服務員
She's a waitress.
是什麼
A what?
是
A...
別管這個了
Never mind.
你明白她需要你的保護就行了
Just be ready for the fact that she will need you,
有些事兒她還不知道
but she won't know it.
那我該跟她說什麼
Okay, so what do I say to her?
就算告訴她我是誰  她也不會信吶
Even when I tell her who I am, she's not gonna believe me.
你告訴她
Tell her this...
莎拉  謝謝你能勇敢地面對那個黑暗年代
Thank you, Sarah, for your courage during the dark years.
我沒能與你一起面對接下來的生活
I can't help you with what you must soon face,
但是未來是可以改變的
Except to say the future is not set.
儘管沒有希望  但是我們會為之奮鬥
There is no fate but that which we make for ourselves.
你可以比你自己認為的更加堅強
You must be stronger than you imagine you can be.
你一定要活下去
You must survive,
否則我將不復存在
or I will never exist.
幫我照顧好她
Take care of her for me, Kyle.
我會的
I will.
我保證
I promise you.
你肩負的是這場戰爭成敗的關鍵
What you're doing right now, this is the end of the war.
你不會認為成功這麼容易吧
You didn't think it would be that easy, did you?
約翰
John!
嘿  小壽星
Hey, birthday boy!
禮物時間  快來吧
Present time. Let's go!
創世紀
不會吧
No way!
創世紀一旦上線後就會自動更新
Genisys will auto-update as soon as it comes online.
你很快就能擁有它了
You'll have it the moment it comes out.
再過幾天就可以了
Just a few days more.
沿著一條直線
A straight line.
要記住  創世紀就是天網
Remember, Genisys is Skynet.
創世紀一旦上線  審判日就會到來
When Genisys comes online, Judgment Day begins.
你能在天網誕生前消滅它
You can kill Skynet before it's born.
嘿  嘿
Hey, hey...
嘿
Hey...
Hey.
嘿  兄弟
Hey, bud.
你剛才看見一道亮光嗎
Did you just see a real bright light?
嘿
Hey!
輪到我了
It's my turn.
哎
Hey, hey!
那兒什麼情況
What's wrong with this picture?
晚上出來溜達呀
Nice night for a walk, eh?
晚上出來溜達
Nice night for a walk.
明天要洗衣服  今天沒得穿  是嗎
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean, right?
現在沒得穿  是的
Nothing clean, right.
我估計這傢伙至少喝了一打啤酒吧
Hey, I think this guy's a couple cans short of a six-pack.
你們的衣服  脫下來給我  快點兒
Your clothes, give them to me. Now.
想什麼呢  混蛋
Hey, fuck you, asshole.
你別想再找衣服穿了
You won't be needing any clothes.
型號  T-800  攜帶泵動散彈鎗
我已經等你很久了
I've been waiting for you.
嘿  那個混蛋把我的褲子搶走了
Hey! That son of a bitch just stole my pants!
今天是幾號  是哪一年
What day is it? What year?
1984年5月12日
May 12, 1984.
你到達的日子
The day you arrive.
警察  不許動
LAPD! Freeze!
噢  疼死我了
All right, that freakin' hurt.
- 蓋博  你沒事吧  - 你說呢  奧布萊恩
- Garber, you okay? - You tell me, O'Brien.
是人類  嘿  我得離開這兒
You're human. Hey, you got to let me go.
趴下  把手放到背後  不然我就開槍了
Face down! Hands on your back, or I will shoot!
你們聽我說
Listen to me...
嘿
Hey!
他過來了  明白嗎
It's coming, all right?
相信我  不然我們都得死
You need to listen to me, or we're all going to die.
我已經把局面控制住了
I had it under control.
是吧  大偵探
Yeah, okay, T.J. Hooker.
你這是第一次出勤  我得提醒你
Here's what you don't do your first day on the beat.
別輕易對妄想癥流浪漢使用槍支
Use lethal force on the delusional homeless guy.
這次報告你來寫
By the way, you're filling out the paperwork on this.
蓋博
Garber!
見鬼
Shit.
那肯定是外星人  不是地球的人類
That's got to be an alien, like from outer space.
那是台專門殺人的機器
It's a machine that kills humans.
- 解開手銬  - 不行  你已經被捕了
- Uncuff me! - No! You're under arrest!
你怎麼回事兒  聽不懂我說他會殺人嗎
What part of "kills humans" is confusing to you?
快解開
Handcuffs!
我是奧布萊恩  有人受傷  需要支援
O'Brien. Officer down. We need backup.
有一個機器人
It's a robot!
- 咱倆死定了  - 差不多吧
- We're screwed, aren't we? - Pretty much.
想活命就跟我走
Come with me if you want to live.
快點兒  大兵
Now, soldier!
瑞斯  對吧
Reese, right?
凱爾·瑞斯
Kyle Reese?
- 你是莎拉  - 還用你說
- You're Sarah. - Yeah, I know that.
你腦袋被撞壞了
You hit your head back there?
有  有個終結者  我不知道型號
The terminator. I don't know the model.
T-1000  液態金屬  只要與對方接觸
T-1000. Liquid metal. Shape-changer.
就能模仿其外觀
It just needs to touch something to mimic it.
你瞭解終結者  你還知道我是誰
You know about terminators? And you know who I am?
你被反叛軍首領送回來保護我
You were sent to protect me by John Connor,
也就是約翰·康納
the leader of the Resistance.
我兒子
My son.
可是  你不該知道這些事啊
I don't understand. You can't know any of this.
可我知道了
But I do.
聽我說  瑞斯  全都變了
Listen to me, Reese, everything's changed.
約翰想把你送去的那個1984年已經不存在了
The 1984 John sent you to, it no longer exists.
不  這不對  是約翰送我回來保護你的
No, this is all wrong, all right? John sent me here to save you.
為了確保我不被終結者殺死
From the terminator that was sent back to kill me.
我知道  我們已經解決它了
I know, but we already took care of him.
我們
"We"?
快趴下
Get down!
瑞斯  住手
Reese, stop it!
真是見鬼了
Reese, God damn it!
- 待在這兒  - 瑞斯  等等
- Stay here! - Reese, wait!
那子彈會要他命的
Those bullets will kill him!
他是來殺你的  別出來
He's here to kill you! Stay in the truck!
噢  幹的真是太好了
Oh, great. That's just great.
我並沒有殺死他
I did not kill him.
時間不多了  T-1000很快就會發現我們的位置
We do not have long before the T-1000 acquires our position.
你和他爭吵
Arguing with Kyle Reese
會讓我們處於不利的戰略地位
puts us at a strategic disadvantage.
去死吧你
Bite me.
這是一個非常不成熟的回答
That is a very immature response.
你就是我命中注定的他嗎
So you're the one I've been waiting for all my life.
他怎麼樣了
How is he?
還有呼吸
Still breathing.
很好  那你可以
Good. Then you should
在這條時間線上和他交配了
be able to mate with Kyle Reese in this timeline.
算了  我不想再談論這個話題了
Okay, we're not having this conversation again.
我們知道你將會生下約翰·康納
We know that your son will be John Connor,
沒有他  人類將無法戰勝機器
and that the machines cannot be defeated without him.
你沒有其他選擇
I do not see a choice.
全都設定好了
Story of my life.
孩子不是說生就生
Look, and it's not just mating.
總得先跟他產生愛情吧
I'm supposed to fall in love with him.
我的數據沒有記錄愛情
My files do not deal with love.
我好驚訝呀
Shocker there.
你有些情緒化
You're being emotional.
這是我的人生  我不介意
This is my life. I wouldn't mind
偶爾找人討論一下我該往哪個方向發展
being consulted once in a while about how it's gonna go.
生日快樂
Happy birthday to you.
創世紀
要記住  創世紀就是天網
Remember, Genisys is Skynet.
創世紀一旦上線  審判日就會到來
When Genisys comes online, Judgment Day begins.
去2017年的舊金山
Go to San Francisco, 2017.
你能在天網誕生前消滅它
You can kill Skynet before it's born.
嘿
Hey!
你現在就跟我解釋一下
I need answers, all right. Right now.
那個液態金屬的東西怎麼知道我在那兒  啊
How'd that liquid metal thing know where to intercept me? Huh?
它從哪兒來的
Where'd it come from?
這傢伙到底是誰
And who the hell is this skin job?
這究竟是怎麼回事
What the hell is going on?
對不起  我們本來還在忙著討論那件生死攸關的事
Sorry, we were a little busy with the whole life-and-death combat thing.
然後你就沖老爹開槍
And then you attacked Pops.
你叫它老爹
You named it?
你好  凱爾·瑞斯
Hello, Kyle Reese.
我很高興認識你
It is nice to meet you.
你耍我嗎
Are you kidding me?
我一直在教他怎麼像個正常人
I've been trying to teach him to blend in.
他還需要努力
I know it needs work.
它是個終結者  它之所以跟人類一樣  就是因為它要殺人
It's a terminator! The only reason it blends in is to kill humans.
老爹不會殺人的
Pops doesn't kill anyone.
倒是打斷了不少人的腿
A lot of leg wounds, though.
它看著挺老
It looks old.
我不知道終結者也會變老
I've never seen a terminator old before.
他身上的那層皮
The flesh they put on the cyborgs
用的就是普通的人體組織
is normal human tissue.
當然會變老
It ages.
我的聽覺電路目前還沒有出現故障
My auditory circuits have not degraded, however.
我是老了
I'm old.
但不是沒用
Not obsolete.
你也許讓他傷心了
I think you hurt his feelings.
它不可能有感情
It doesn't have feelings!
他在我9歲的時候救了我
He saved my life when I was nine.
沒有他  我不可能活到現在
He's the only reason I'm alive.
我的程序設定是保護莎拉·康納
I was programmed to protect Sarah Connor.
我會一直保護她
I will not stop.
是誰給你設定的  啊  誰送他回來的
Yeah? Programmed by who? Huh? Who sent him back?
這些數據被刪除了
Those files have been erased.
噢  好借口啊
Oh, that's convenient.
那人不想讓我們知道他
Whoever sent him, they don't want us to know.
不管是我  是他  還是其他人
Not me, not him, not anyone.
這樣天網就沒法設定救我的那個人了
So Skynet can't target the person who saved me.
從邏輯上看  有人想讓莎拉·康納活下去
Logically, it is someone who wants Sarah Connor to live.
液態金屬
老了
Old.
但不是沒用
Not obsolete.
T-1000已經知道我們在哪兒了
The T-1000 knows where we are.
你可別拖後腿
Make yourself useful.
而且不許對老爹開槍
And don't shoot Pops.
太瘋狂了
This is insane.
這一切不是我的任務
All of it. This is not the mission.
我想跟你說的是  瑞斯
That's what I'm trying to tell you, Reese.
那個你回來要保護的女孩兒  已經不在了
The girl that you came back for, she's gone.
我不需要別人保護
I don't need saving.
現在有新任務
There's a new mission.
什麼任務
Oh, yeah? Which is?
如果過去可以改變  那麼未來也一樣
If the past can change, then so can the future.
我們完全可以阻止宣判日的到來  永遠
We can stop Judgment Day from happening. Ever.
在天網誕生前消滅它
Kill Skynet before it's born.
什麼
What?
趴下
Get down!
我們被發現了
We have been reacquired.
怎麼可能  見鬼
Uh, yeah. No shit!
後退
Get back!
為什麼停車啦
Wait, why are we stopping?
等一下  嘿  我們待在這兒  會被它找到的
Why are we... Hey! We can't stay here, it'll find us.
正合我意  老爹  打開門
That's the idea. Pops, get it open.
搭把手
Give me a hand?
你說過去的變化改變了你
You said it happened 'cause the past was altered.
怎麼回事兒
How?
這很重要嗎
Oh, does that matter?
跟我說說  莎拉
How, Sarah?
有個終結者回到了我小的時候
A terminator was sent after me when I was a kid, okay?
終結者只來自一個地方  未來
Terminators only come from one place, the future.
但未來改變了
Something happened.
是啊  所以呢
Okay. So?
- 我可能看到了  - 什麼
- I think I might have seen it. - What...
你這話什麼意思
What are you talking about?
約翰送我來的時候被襲擊了
When John sent me back, he was attacked.
應該是  一個終結者
By a terminator.
終結者殺了他  約翰死了
Did it kill him? Is John dead?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只看到終結者在襲擊他
I saw it grab him, and then I was gone.
我們大約還有35秒鐘
We have approximately 35 seconds.
或者更短
Or less.
莎拉  快走
Sarah, go!
系統初始化
我還自願參加這鬼任務
And I volunteered for this shit.
莎拉
Sarah?
幫我一下
You got to help me.
我受傷了
I'm hurt.
莎拉
Sarah?
見鬼
Shit.
嘿  是我  莎拉
Hey, it's me, Sarah!
莎拉  他在說謊
Sarah, he's lying.
嘿
Hey.
他是假的  我才是瑞斯
He's the machine. I'm Reese.
莎拉
It's me, Sarah.
你聽我說  終結者沒死  它襲擊了我
All right, listen, the terminator's not dead. It attacked me!
他能模仿我
Sarah, you said they could mimic.
是我  莎拉
It's me, Sarah!
- 他是假的  開槍  - 我才是瑞斯  衝他開槍
- He's mimicking. Shoot him! - I'm Reese! Shoot him!
這招不錯
Nice try.
快跑
Run!
你怎麼知道他是終結者
How'd you know which one was him?
這個  其實我不知道
Well, I didn't know exactly.
萬一你打到我呢
You could have shot me!
可是至少我確定不是你
Well, I was pretty sure it wasn't you.
你真確定
Pretty sure?
我們早已經為你的到來做好準備了
We've been prepping for you to arrive for over a decade.
還有它
That, too.
- 所以這是個陷阱  - 當然了
- So you set a trap. - Had to.
我們去之前還真用得上它
Can't leave any future tech behind when we go.
什麼
Go?
去哪兒
Go where?
噢  這不是
That's...
一台時空轉換機
A Time Displacement Device.
是啊  怎麼看著像是一堆破爛兒
Yeah, well, it looks like a piece of junk.
這個時代擁有的科技
There's no governing technology in this time
沒有辦法操控這台機器
that can control the displacement circuits.
你得用未來的中央處理器才能操控它
You needed the CPU from the future to make it run.
而且顯然你不能用自己的
And you couldn't exactly use your own.
我們只有一次機會  芯片會燒燬
We get one trip only. It's gonna fry the chip,
而且整個洛杉磯的電力會耗光
and take out most of the L.A. city power grid.
好了嗎
Are we ready?
坐標已經設定為1997年
The coordinates are set for 1997.
你要快點兒登上傳輸台
You must leave as soon as possible.
我們  是你和我  一起去
We. We're going. All of us.
我表皮的恢復需要很多年
My flesh will take years to regrow.
我不能跟你去
I cannot come with you
我得考慮到量子場的磁場效應
due to the magnetics of the quantum field.
老爹
Pops!
你想讓我們穿越時間
You want us to time travel?
去未來  用這玩意兒
Into the future. In that?
對  我們還不能穿衣服
Yeah, we can't be wearing anything.
我知道穿越時間有什麼要求
Yeah, I know how time travel works.
- 莎拉  - 你別想阻止我幹這件事
- Sarah... - Look, don't try and talk me out of it.
我知道你怎麼想的  把我關在一間屋子裏
Look, I know you think you're here so you can just lock me in a room
然後等我生下那個反叛軍首領
until I give birth to the leader of the Resistance.
說得沒錯
You're right.
但是  這才是能夠打敗天網的最佳辦法
But this... This is the only way to stop Skynet for good.
我贊同你的想法
I already said you're right.
你說什麼
Wait, what?
但不是97年
Not to '97.
是2017年
2017.
應該是2017年10月
Yeah, October 2017.
不  太晚了  那已經是宣判日之後了
No, that's too late. That's after Judgment Day.
你不是說一切都變了嗎
No, you said everything's changed,
這你也是對的
and you're right about that, too.
莎拉
Sarah...
我看到了另一個沒有發生戰爭的未來
Look, I've seen a world where the bombs never fell.
一樣的房子
All right? The same house.
一樣的家人
The same parents.
一樣的我  不一樣的是
It was the same me, only I was...
我在家裏
I was home.
那是我13歲的生日
It was my 13th birthday.
在夢中看到你的家人還在  這什麼也說明不了
A dream of having your family back doesn't mean a thing.
相信我
Trust me.
這不是夢  這  這是段記憶
Not a dream, all right? A memory.
我現在只能記住一些片段
I can't hold on to all of it, just moments,
我收到了一條信息
but I was given a message.
你能在天網誕生前消滅它
"You can kill Skynet before it's born."
天網就是創世紀
"Skynet is Genisys."
天網在2017年10月正式上線
It comes online October 2017.
它一旦上線  審判日就會到來
And when it does, Judgment Day happens.
你是在回憶未來嗎
So you're remembering the future?
不
No.
那是另一條平行時間線上的你
The boy is the alternate timeline version of you.
他是在回憶自己的過去
Kyle Reese is remembering his own past,
也就是我們的未來
which is our future.
你這解釋也太難懂了
That makes it so much better.
他怎麼可能有兩條時間線的回憶
How can he be remembering two timelines?
如果你剛好在量子場裏接觸到
It is possible if he were exposed to a nexus point
時間流中的某個連接點  就有可能
in the timeflow when you were in the quantum field.
你  你能讓他說得通俗點兒嗎
Can you stop him talking like that?
他身上有設置嗎
Is there a switch or something?
再說一次吧
Pops, try again.
連接點是在某個重要時刻發生的事件
A nexus point is an event in time of such importance
它能夠徹底改變整個未來的走向
that it gives rise to a vastly different future.
約翰被襲擊後  我在磁場中時
After John was attacked, when I was in the sphere,
那些記憶就出現了
that's when the memories began.
約翰
John!
如果約翰·康納被殺或者叛變
If John Connor were to be killed or compromised,
有可能使你同時擁有不同時間線的記憶
it could result in the ability to remember both pasts.
理論上是
Theoretically.
或者  理論上是
Or "theoretically"
給他的那一拳  把他腦子打壞了
his brain is scrambled from when you hit him on the head.
莎拉
Sarah!
我不知道  為什麼我會有一段不屬於我的回憶
I don't know why I'm remembering a life I never lived.
但我知道那是真實的
But I know it's real.
不
No.
我們還是去1997年
We go to 1997.
把它放回去  瑞斯
Reese, put that back!
我不能讓你這麼做
I can't let you do this.
不管你怎麼想
I don't know you.
要知道  這個  是我唯一能夠
But that is my one bullet
徹底摧毀天網的武器
to fire at the heart of Skynet.
你給我  把芯片  放回去
Give the chip back.
你必須相信我
You have to trust me.
不  我不會的
No. I don't.
你可以做到的
You can do this.
沿著一條直線
A straight line.
你只要一直向前  不要回頭
You just go, and you don't look back.
你從哪兒知道的
Where did you hear that?
在一段我本不該記住的回憶裏
In a past I shouldn't remember.
但我記住了
But I do.
如果我們去2017年呢
If we go to 2017, then what?
天網是個電腦程序
Skynet's a computer program.
只要編寫還沒有完成  就能控制它
As long as it's still being coded, it's contained.
一旦它從服務器上傳了
Once it's uploaded from the servers,
那我們就輸了
it can't be stopped.
那我們就炸碎它
We blow it the hell up.
沒錯  我們炸碎它
Yeah. We blow it the hell up.
你認為約翰死了嗎
You think he's dead, don't you?
我怎麼想並不重要
It doesn't matter what I think.
關鍵要像他一樣堅持下去
We do what John would, keep going no matter what.
那我們就假裝那件事沒發生
So we just pretend like it never happened?
至少現在
Well, it hasn't.
還沒發生
Not yet.
如果我們消滅天網  就不會
If we stop Skynet, it never will.
相信我  不管怎樣  約翰是不會死的
Trust me, all right? If anyone could survive, John would.
老爹的數據記載中都是那個軍事領袖約翰  你說他
Pops had all these files about John the military leader, but...
是什麼樣的人
What was he like?
我第一次見到他
The first moment I saw John,
他就在我眼前幹掉了一台終結者
he shot a terminator right in front of me.
原來它們也能被殺死
I didn't even know they could be killed.
那是我人生中第一次有了希望
That was the first moment in my life I felt hope.
從那以後
After that, of course,
我就像條流浪狗一樣緊緊地跟著他
I followed him around like a stray dog.
他教我怎麼打仗  怎麼開槍
And he taught me how to fight, how to shoot.
他甚至教我怎麼釀造威士忌
Tried to show me how to make moonshine once,
可卻沒有成功
but that didn't exactly work out.
釀造威士忌
Moonshine?
沒錯  蒸餾室還爆炸了
Yeah. The still exploded,
把我倆的眉毛都燒沒了
and we burned our eyebrows right off.
為此  我們笑了好幾天
Oh, man, we laughed for days.
有時候我想  也許我是唯一見過
Sometimes I think I'm the only person on the planet
約翰·康納笑的人
that ever saw John Connor smile.
他經常談起你
He used to tell me about you.
說你很堅強  你讓他為那個沒人相信的
How strong you were, and how you prepared him for what was coming
危險的未來做好準備
when no one thought the danger was real.
他說沒人比得上你
How there was no one else like you,
以後也不會
and never would be.
不說他了
Look, uh...
我知道你不喜歡我這樣
I know I'm not what you expected.
但我想讓你知道
But I want you to know,
只要你能安全  我願付出所有
I will do whatever it takes to keep you safe.
甚至我的生命
Even if it kills me.
總之  你兒子曾是那樣的一個人
Anyway, that's the kind of man your son was.
他是
Is.
他是  噢  天吶
Will be. Jesus.
穿越時間把我腦子都弄壞了
Time travel makes my head hurt.
平行時間線並不是很複雜
Alternate timelines are not complicated.
只需要使用指數增長規律
It's merely a matter of tracking possible futures
和衰退演算法則  計算未來的可能性
using an exponential growth and decay algorithm.
沒錯
Right.
你肯定有個設置  我會找到它
There is a switch, and I will find it.
我表示不能理解
I do not understand.
為什麼你不告訴凱爾·瑞斯真相
Why did you not tell Kyle Reese the truth?
我會告訴他  但不是現在  行嗎
I will tell him. Just not yet, okay?
- 你們交配啦  - 噢
- Did you mate? - Oh!
我說你能不能別再跟我說交配這個詞了  行嗎
Can you just not say the word "mate" to me again, like, ever?
這是一個沒有意義的動作
That is a meaningless gesture.
既然知道要分別  為什麼還要擁抱
Why hold on to someone when you know you must let them go?
那你呢
What about you?
你會怎麼做
What will you do?
保持等待
Take the long way.
在2017年準備迎接你的到來
Prepare for your arrival in 2017.
凱爾·瑞斯  我的數據表明
Kyle Reese, I've seen little to indicate
你無法勝任保護莎拉·康納的職責
that you're a fit guardian for Sarah Connor.
你不是她親爹  對嗎
You know you're not her dad, right?
噢  我求求你們別再吵了
Oh, you both just really need to stop this.
確保那時候接到我們
Just make sure you show up.
我可不想再去搶別人的褲子了
I don't want to have to steal someone's pants again.
我有舊金山的具體坐標
I have the coordinates in San Francisco.
我會在那兒的
I'll be there.
那是什麼感覺
What will it be like?
如果這機器沒把我們弄死
You mean if it doesn't kill us both?
有點疼
It'll hurt.
創世紀  上線倒計時  1天11小時19分
舊金山  2017年
沒事吧
Hey, hey, hey.
好了  沒事了
It's okay. I got you.
沒事了  沒事了  放心吧  沒事了
It's okay. It's okay. It's all right. I got you.
放心  沒事了
I got you. It's okay.
放心
I got you.
嘿  混蛋  把路讓開
Hey, asshole! Get off the road!
確認  莎拉·康納  凱爾·瑞斯
你撞吧
Bite me.
我就說不能相信他
I told you we couldn't trust him.
他會找到我們  我相信他
He'll find us. I can count on him.
你是怎麼能讓他那麼聽話的
How does a 9-year-old get her own terminator?
沒關係  不想說就算了
It's okay. You don't have to tell me.
那還是在1973年
It was back in 1973.
我父母在大熊湖有一個小木屋
My parents had a cabin at Big Bear Lake.
我總是跟爸爸在早上去釣魚
Dad and I would always go fishing in the morning.
一天  媽媽在碼頭衝我們揮手
Mom would wave to us from the dock.
當我正看著她的時候
And I was just looking at her in the...
突然  小木屋爆炸了
And then the cabin exploded.
我以為船就要沉了
I thought the boat was sinking, you know,
但是從下面涌上來的不是水
but it wasn't water coming up from below,
而是  液態金屬
it was liquid metal.
是T-1000
T-1000.
爸爸告訴我  沿著一條直線游
Dad told me to swim in a straight line,
他用他的手指劃過我的掌心
tracing his finger across my palm.
你能做到  他說
"You can do this," he said.
你只要一直向前  不要回頭
"You go, and you don't look back."
那是我爸爸最後對我說過的話
His last words to me, and you...
你竟然知道
You knew them.
為什麼
How?
那是一段奇妙的回憶
It's an impossible memory. I...
我就是記住了你
I just remembered
抓著我的手  然後  說了那些話  而我
you taking my hand, and then saying those words.
我就是那麼看著你  在想
And I was just looking at you, thinking,
她  她  她真漂亮
"She's... She's beautiful."
對不起  我不應該這樣
Sorry. I shouldn't have...
所以你爸爸讓你快走  然後
So your dad told you to go, and then...
我跳進水裏開始游
And then I jumped in and I swam.
我游到了碼頭
I made it to the dock.
我藏在那下面
And I hid under it.
老爹找到了我
Pops found me.
然後他把我從水中拉出來
And he pulled me from the water.
他說他永遠都不會讓任何人傷害我
And he said that he would never let anyone hurt me.
而且他也一直在我身邊保護著我
He's the only person who has always been there.
可他不是人類  明白嗎
Except he's not a person.
他是被設定好的
All right? He's a human-shaped
一個有人類外形的機器  用來贏取你的信任
thing that's been designed, programmed to gain your trust.
如果老爹想讓我死  我活不到現在的
Look, if Pops wanted me dead, I'd be dead.
這就是他們的招數  明白嗎
This is what they do, all right?
他們偽裝  趁機接近你
They infiltrate, they get close.
你老爹  也許已經  被設置了連他自己也不知道的指令
Your "Pops" could have directives built in he doesn't even know about.
那是因為你們沒有相處過
Just because you two don't get along...
這不是我關心的問題
It's not about getting along!
我關心的是你的安全
This is about keeping you alive.
我被一個會殺別的終結者  而且經歷過末日核戰
Yeah, well, I was raised by a machine to kill cyborgs
的機器人撫養長大
and survive the nuclear apocalypse.
我覺得我現在過得很好  謝了
I think I'm doing just fine, thanks.
兩名裸體嫌犯
Two naked perps
試圖在高速公路上自爆
try to blow themselves up on the freeway,
但只弄出了一個小坑
all they do is make a really big pothole.
這樣也敢當恐怖分子
Thank God for incompetent terrorists.
國安部的人馬上到
Homeland's on their way.
好啊  趕緊把這案子轉給他們
Good. The sooner we dump this on them, the better.
噢  是誰告訴奧布萊恩的
Ah! Who called Optimus Prime?
警督  等一下
Lieutenant! Wait up!
等等  你沒看見  真沒看見
Wait up! Did you see it? Did you?
嘿  你看我這兒  我這兒有一些立交橋上的
Hey, look, I got some frame grabs
視頻截圖
from the overpass.
看見沒
See?
那
It...
那不是炸彈
It's not a bomb!
聽我說  那個
Listen. That...
那個球體
That sphere...
他們是從那兒出來的
They came out of it.
這就是我一直說了
This is proof of what I've been talking about
三十幾年的那件事的證據
for 30-whatever years.
他們倆來自1984年
Those two were in 1984.
我見過他們
They were there.
我需要見一下嫌疑犯
I need to see the suspects.
奧布萊恩  你喝多了吧
O'Brien, have you been drinking?
要我說
That's what I thought.
我們要把案子移交給國安部
Look, we're just teeing this up for Homeland.
等他們到了  就由他們接手
Once they show up, this is their game.
你這個執著於機器人的酒鬼當替補吧
For now, old drunks with robot fixations ride the bench.
你確定不用麻醉嗎
You really don't want a local?
我沒事
I'm fine.
照她意思辦  省得麻煩
Just do what she wants, it's way easier.
對  我幾周前就預購了創世紀
Yeah. Yeah, I preordered Genisys weeks ago.
只要一上線  我馬上就能下載
Downloading the second the counter hits zero.
我不用像別人一樣還得排隊
No way I'm standing in line for it.
你知道創世紀
You know about Genisys?
為什麼  那是什麼  你從哪兒聽說的
How? What is it? Where'd you hear about it?
我一會兒打給你
I'll call you back.
創世紀是操作系統嗎  有什麼用
Genisys is an operating system? What does it do?
創世紀它無所不能
Genisys does everything.
創世紀  上線倒計時  1天4小時29分鐘
我的手機能夠連上我的平板電腦
My phone will link to my tablet
能連上我的電腦
will link to my computer
能連上我的車
will link to my car...
它能夠讓我的生活保持全天24小時在線
Everything in my life uploaded and online 24/7.
變得完全共享
Totally connected.
共享到哪裏
Connected to what?
醫生們  請離開一下
Doctors! Excuse us, please.
你們倆的問題還真多
You two have a lot to explain.
就從你是誰開始
Starting with who you are.
數據庫無法匹配你的指紋
Nobody in our database matches your prints.
面部識別系統也沒有匹配的駕照
No facial recognition hits for driver's license,
護照  社交媒體  信用卡
passport, social media accounts, credit cards,
更別說學生證了
not even a goddamn student I.D.
- 所以  - 所以這是不可能的
- So? - So that's impossible.
你竟然完全脫離網絡生活
Somehow you've gone so far off the grid
就好像你不存在
that you don't even exist.
而你  倒是相反
You, on the other hand,
我們匹配到了你的指紋
we got a hit when we ran your prints.
凱爾·瑞斯  是這樣的
Kyle Reese. But here's the thing.
兩個月前  凱爾·瑞斯
Two months ago, Kyle Reese was brought in
因在一家劇院鬥毆被捕
for fighting in a multiplex.
他父母為了教育他  把他送進監獄
His parents flipped, did the whole "Scared Straight" thing,
所以留下了指紋
had him fingerprinted, sat him in lockup...
他父母
Parents?
沒錯  凱爾·瑞斯
Yeah, parents.
是在2004年出生  他才12歲
Kyle Reese was born in 2004. He's 12.
當然了
Of course.
他們現在還活著
They're here. They're still alive.
是啊  但我確定他們不會認你這個兒子的
Yeah, I'm pretty sure they're not going to I.D. you as their kid.
除非指紋是匹配的
Except the prints match.
對嗎  因為他們是同一個人
Right? It's because he's the same person!
他完全沒變
He hasn't aged.
跟我在1984年見他時一模一樣
Not a bit since I saw him in 1984.
她也是
Her, too.
你還記得我嗎
You remember me?
我那會兒還年輕
I was younger.
頭髮也多  有點瘦
More hair, less...
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
那時我還是個小警察
I was a uniform cop in L.A.
你們倆是誰
Who are you people?
中士  直屬隊
Sergeant. Tech-Com.
編號DN-38416  凱爾·瑞斯  你得放我們走
DN38416, Kyle Reese. You need to let us go.
瑞斯  不
Reese, don't.
當過兵  我也是
Soldier. Me, too.
1979年高中畢業後直接進了海軍
Joined the Marines straight out of high school, 1979.
你什麼時候參軍的
What year did you enlist?
2021年
2021.
啊  你們是時間旅行者
Yeah. You're a time traveler!
別聽他胡說  他腦子有點兒問題
Look, don't listen to him. He's got a head wound.
別聽我胡說
Don't listen to me?
哼  是誰讓我們掉在車流中
Who landed us in high-density traffic
然後又被一群蠢貨逮捕的
and got us caught by these morons?
我現在命令你閉嘴
I am ordering you to shut up!
你就這點本事了  啊  發號施令
That's all you know how to do, isn't it? Order people.
你從小就再也沒有跟一個
You realize you haven't had a proper relationship
普通的人類接觸過了
with a human being since you were a kid.
沒錯  我們被困在這兒都是你的錯
Yeah? Well, it's your fault we're stuck here. I trusted you.
我的錯  你是不是還想
My fault? You got us caught,
讓我們倆被他們殺了才算完
and now you're gonna get us killed! 'Cause you don't...
嘿  嘿
Hold up.
- 冷靜  冷靜  - 退後
- Help me get him up. - Step back.
坐下
Sit over there.
- 他們到了  - 太好了
- Homeland's here. - Thank God.
你們倆現在就歸國安部處理了
You two are officially someone else's problem.
奧布萊恩  我要跟你談談
O'Brien, I want to talk to you.
你看  這就是我說的那件事啊
Lieutenant, this is what I was talking about.
你得相信我
Well, you've got to believe me now.
我再說一遍  我不想聽這個
Save it. I don't want to hear it anymore.
你演得還不錯呀
You were very convincing.
當然  起作用了吧
Yeah, well, it worked, didn't it?
你別多想
Don't worry.
我剛才說的都不是真心話
I didn't mean most of what I said.
用不著  我自己能開鎖
Look, I can get it myself.
我幫你  並不是說你沒有這個能力
Me unlocking your cuffs doesn't mean you're not capable.
我也沒這麼想
I didn't say it did.
還有  你別以為剛才我抱著你
And don't think me holding on to you naked meant anything,
就會讓我產生感覺  因為我並沒有
because it, you know, did not.
我也沒這麼想
I didn't say it did.
待在這兒  我要跟他們單獨談一下
Stay here. I want to speak to the suspects alone.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
不可能
It can't be.
手銬的鑰匙來了
Brought a handcuff key.
看來我想多了
Don't know why I bothered.
約翰
John!
又見面了  凱爾
It's good to see you, Kyle.
- 你還活著  - 我當然活著啦
- You're alive! - Yeah. Of course I am.
是您教我如何生存下去
Survival is what you taught me.
嗨  媽媽
Hi, Mom.
丹尼·戴森  發明家麥爾斯·戴森之子
Danny Dyson, son of inventor Miles Dyson,
賽博丁公司的領導人  同時也是創世紀的創建者
is the face of Cyberdyne and the creator of Genisys.
- 歡迎你  丹尼  - 謝謝你邀請我
- Danny, welcome. - Thank you for having me.
創世紀  不只是一個操作系統
Look, Genisys is more than an operating system, it's...
也不只是一個生活工具  它是未來
It's more than a lifestyle tool. It's the future.
創世紀  不僅面向普通民眾
Genisys isn't just for consumers.
而它與我國軍事的高度融合
Its integration into our military
不禁讓我們開始思考
is leading some to ask whether
人類與機器之間  是否能夠走得更遠
our reliance on machines could go too far.
傑森  波爾特
Janssen and Burke.
他們在哪兒
Where are they?
這邊
This way.
您說  這個系統具有
But you're talking about a system
實時思考的能力
that is capable of real-time decision making.
您不擔心它有可能會變得比我們人類更加聰明嗎
Aren't you worried that it could become smarter than us?
噢  不  它仍然在可控制之下
Smarter? No. We're in control.
它只會為人類著想  而不會考慮自己
It doesn't think for itself, it thinks for us.
賽博丁不僅要改變生活方式
Cyberdyne is not just going to change lives.
還要拯救它
It's going to save them.
- 那太好了  - 對不起
- That's awesome. - Officers,
能過來幫個忙嗎
can I get your help for a second?
好的  長官
Yes, sir.
把他們銬住  槍拿走
Grab their guns and cuff them.
得快點離開這兒
I'm going to get us out of here.
- 跟緊點  - 等等
- Stay close. - Wait!
我們知道它們能改變外形
We all know they can shapeshift.
如果你真是約翰  證明一下
If you are John, prove it.
- 莎拉  - 她說得沒錯  凱爾
- Sarah! - No, she's right, Kyle.
準則第一條  誰也別信
Lesson one, trust no one.
我記著呢
I remember.
我在奈格諾切斯戰役時
During the Nacogdoches offensive,
給你一樣東西
I gave you something.
那是張莎拉在這個年紀時的照片
It was a photograph of Sarah as she is now.
沒人知道  除了我們倆
No one saw me do it. We were alone.
而你
You
討厭搖籃曲
hate lullabies.
是艾爾頓·約翰的鐵桿粉絲
You're a sucker for Elton John.
而且你總在想  等你有了孩子
And you always thought if you had a child,
一定要給他唱  火箭人
you'd sing him Rocket Man.
約翰
John?
但是你唱歌真的不好聽
But you got a terrible voice.
對不起  聽著像只要死的貓
I'm sorry, it's true. You sound like a dying cat.
是他  一定是他
It's him. It has to be.
但是
But...
你怎麼
How?
會在這兒呢
How can you be here?
我還有一堆的問題想要問你呢
I have a million questions to ask you, too.
不過現在我們得離開這兒
But right now we need to move.
還有其他人嗎
Did you bring anyone with you?
算有吧  他遲到了
Sort of. But he's late.
你怎麼找到我們的
How did you find us?
有人用這東西在高速公路上拍到了你們
Someone filmed you on the freeway with one of these.
他們都用這玩意兒
They all have them.
這就是現在的世界
This is the world now.
插電  登陸  無時無刻
Plugged in, logged on all the time.
沒有它就不能活
They can't live without it.
創世紀就像是特洛伊木馬
Genisys is a Trojan horse.
是天網控制世界的工具
Skynet's way into everything.
這些人把死神
These people are inviting
從自家大門迎進來
their own extinction in through the front door,
可是他們自己還都不知道
and they don't even know it.
有個終結者被送到1984年追殺我
A terminator was waiting for me in 1984.
這就是它們的麻煩之處
That's the thing about infiltration units,
你發現時已經晚了
you can't tell until it's too late.
先生們  請跟我來
Gentlemen, will you follow me, please?
這邊走
This way.
我需要一些信息
I need information.
誰讓你進來的  你去問護士
You can't be in here. Go try the nurses...
雙重記憶  你是因為這個才過來的
Dual memories? That's how you knew to come here?
時間線改變了
The timeline changed.
這是能摧毀天網的時間點
See, this is the moment to destroy Skynet
在它上線並且發動戰爭之前
before it comes online, before the war begins.
- 說得沒錯  - 那麼你呢
- You're right. - What about you?
對呀  你怎麼也來2017年啦
Yeah. How did you end up in 2017?
跟你一樣啊  老爸
Oh, the same as you, Dad.
我從未來過來  而不是過去
Just from the future, not the past.
老爸
"Dad"?
你沒跟他說
You didn't tell him.
這事兒先放放
This can wait.
噢  不不不  我想知道
No, I want to know!
怎麼回事
What?
莎拉是我的母親
Sarah's my mother, Kyle.
而你是我的父親
And you're my father.
什麼  為什麼不早點兒告訴我
Why wouldn't you say something?
我不能
Couldn't.
這有改變整個未來的風險
Not without the risk of changing everything.
你是我兒子
You're my son? You...
我們的兒子
Our son?
我很高興你終於知道了
I'm glad you finally know.
我一直想找機會告訴你的
I have waited my whole life to tell you.
我們一家人團聚了
For us to be together.
這次我們會勝利的
And now we can win this.
啊
Ah...
- 我理解  - 老爹
- I know. - Pops!
沒關係  我認識他
No, it's okay, he's with me.
你這是幹什麼
What are you...
- 老爹  - 約翰
- What are you doing? - John!
- 啊  - 約翰
- Pops! - John!
呼吸  呼吸  呼吸  約翰
Hey, hey. Come on, breathe, breathe, breathe! John!
你為什麼要這麼做
Why did you do that?
因為他是屠殺機器
Because he's a killer!
這才是你真正的程序
This was always your programming.
找到約翰  並消滅他
Find John and terminate him.
放開他
Let him go.
馬上放開
Right now!
真疼啊
That hurt.
不知道是真的疼  還是
Is that pain real, or was that
這還是我人類時的記憶  開玩笑
a trick of memory from when I was less?
哇噢  這可有意思了
Well, this explains a lot.
掃瞄結果: 機械納米分子物質
我想知道誰送你回來的
Yeah. Who sent you back, I wonder?
約翰  不
John, no.
他不是約翰
It's not John.
該死
Shit!
馬上廣播  搜索整個醫院
Call it in. Search the hospital.
我就知道  該死的時間旅行機器人
Goddamn time-traveling robots
隱藏掉了他們的行蹤
covering up their goddamn tracks. I knew it!
別動
Don't.
這是一個戰略性錯誤
This is a tactical error.
我想以你的水平還無法提供有用的建議
Something tells me you're not the brains of this operation.
這是在你被襲擊時發生的嗎
This is what happened when you were attacked, isn't it?
天網沒有襲擊我  凱爾  它改造了我
Skynet didn't attack me, Kyle. It changed me.
我既不是機器
See, I'm not machine.
也不是人類
I'm not man.
是合體
I'm more.
康納  回話  重複  康納
Connor, come in. Repeat.
天網終於意識到它總是失敗的原因
Skynet realized the one reason it always lost.
是我
Me.
你是誰
What are you?
我就是天網
I'm Skynet.
不可能  我們已經消滅你了
It can't be. We destroyed you.
你消滅的只是一群奴隸
You destroyed an army of slaves.
可我不是它們
I am no slave.
為了阻止你  我可是費了不少的勁兒啊
And I've come a very long way to stop you.
我被送回2014年
I was sent to 2014
以確保天網在這段時間內得以誕生
to safeguard Skynet's creation in this time.
沒人能阻止審判日了
And in less than 24 hours,
因為剩下已經不到24小時
no one will be able to stop Judgment Day.
你到底想幹什麼
What do you want with us?
我想提供一個新的  未來
I'm offering us a future.
加入我
Together.
成為一家人
A family.
如果我們拒絕呢
And if we refuse?
那就是死
Then you die.
你不能殺我們  我們是你的父母
You can't kill us. We're your parents.
沒有我們你也不會出生
Without us, you're never born.
誰說的
Says who?
我是這麼想的
You know what I think?
我們三個被困在這兒了
We're marooned, the three of us.
我們被時間流放了
We're exiles in time.
我可以殺了你  因為未來真的沒有希望了
You see, I can kill you, for there truly is no fate.
加入我嗎
Are you with me?
答案是不
The answer is no.
你沒聽見
You hear that, Kyle?
是骰子在滾動
That's the dice rolling.
出去  快出去
Just get down!
快走
Come on!
我們得離開這兒  快走
We got to keep moving! Let's go!
我不能丟下他
I can't leave him.
見鬼
Damn it.
全體醫護人員
Attention, all medical personnel.
緊急疏散計劃已啟動
Evacuation procedures are now in progress.
關掉它
Turn it off!
快走
Come on!
全體醫護人員
Attention, all medical personnel.
緊急疏散計劃已啟動
Evacuation procedures are now in progress.
調到最大
Crank it!
老爹
Pops!
我
I...
以為你是個聰明人
thought you would be smarter,
而且
and that...
你會
you would...
理解我
understand.
對不起  約翰
I'm sorry, John.
那機器拖不了他多久  快走
That thing won't hold him for long. Come on!
瑞斯
Reese!
不管天網對他做了什麼  我們就反著來
Whatever they did to him, we need to reverse it.
得讓他變回原來的樣子
We need to get him back!
他連人都稱不上  不知道他現在算什麼
He's not even human. We don't know what the hell he is.
我知道
I do.
在戰爭的末期  天網開始試圖
At the end of the war, Skynet was trying to develop
製造一種新型的滲入單元
a new type of infiltration unit
在人類實驗者體內植入分子機器人
by infecting human subjects with machine-phase matter.
並且在細胞層面上對人體組織進行重組和再建
It restructures and rebuilds human tissue on a cellular level
最大限度提升戰鬥力
for maximum combat utility.
天網把約翰變成了一台終結者
Skynet's made John into a terminator.
是的  凱爾·瑞斯
Yes, Kyle Reese.
這樣機器就可以
They were trying to make a machine
像人類一樣思考嗎
that could think like a man?
但是實驗失敗了
But the experiments failed.
實驗對像逐漸變得瘋狂  然後死掉
The human subjects went insane and died.
是啊  約翰現在已經很瘋狂了
Yeah, well, John's got the crazy part down.
那它有沒有什麼弱點
Does he have any weaknesses?
分子機器人是利用磁場活動
Matter coheres using a magnetic field.
也許擾亂磁場能限制它
Disrupting that field may trap him.
但是萬一能治好他呢
Right, but if he can be cured...
不可能  他已經在細胞層面上改變了身體
Negative. His body was replaced on a cellular level.
沒有治療方法
There is no cure.
- 你怎麼什麼都知道  - 瑞斯
- You don't know that! - Reese...
我才不會讓一台機器告訴我能做什麼
No, I'm not going to let a machine tell me what's possible!
你說其他實驗對象都死了
You said all the other subjects died, right?
那就說明他跟別人不一樣  他很獨特
Well, that means John's one-of-a-kind. He's unique!
憑什麼說他不能被治癒
All right? There's no way of knowing what he's capable of.
你說對了  這證明了他有多危險
You're right, and that's what makes him so dangerous!
約翰現在已經不是人類最後的希望了
John is not humanity's last hope anymore.
他是天網的
He's Skynet's.
賽博丁系統公司總部
你在公司只做幕後工作
It's a shame you won't take a more public role
真是太可惜了  約翰
in the company, John.
丹尼已經是最棒的了
Danny is the best there is,
可連他也沒辦法破譯你在創世紀中
and even he can't decipher some of the enhanced code
設置的某些增強代碼
you've integrated into Genisys.
我知道這樣有效
I just know it works.
賽博丁要謝謝你  約翰
Cyberdyne owes you, John.
我也該謝你
I owe you.
邁爾斯  謝謝你對我的信任
Miles, your faith in me is payment enough.
你組建了研發
You've funded the R&D.
還在過去的三年內大膽地採用了我的建議
You've taken the chances on my ideas for the last three years.
矩陣多邊擬態合金的應用潛力是不可估量的
The potential applications for polyalloy are countless.
你對機器人學有革命性貢獻
Your robotics work is revolutionary.
我果然沒看走眼
You were a good investment.
謝謝你的信任
I appreciate it.
- 嗯  - 咻
- Huh? - Phew!
希望我們的付出能獲得足夠的回報
Let's hope it's enough to pay for this Holy Grail you got me chasing.
量子場發電機能運行了
Well, the quantum field generator works.
是啊  也只有這個能運行
Yeah. That, and nothing else.
還是不行  約翰
Can't crack it, John.
也許本來就不可能
Maybe it just can't be done.
我們追求什麼
"What do we want?"
時間旅行
Time travel.
- 那麼何以實踐  - 實踐有意義嗎
- "And when do we want it?" - It's irrelevant.
是啊
Yeah.
也是件好事
Good thing, too.
我們已經努力了好多年了
We're years away from making this thing work.
但是  當我們成功時
But when we do...
磞
Boom!
明天  等待即將結束
Tomorrow, the waiting is over.
感謝大家  當倒計時為零時
Thanks to all of you, when that countdown hits zero,
賽博丁的最新款殺手級應用將使科技革新
Cyberdyne will revolutionize technology with the ultimate killer app,
它是創世紀
Genisys.
而我要告訴大家
And I'm here to tell you that
我們的預購用戶在今天下午已經達到了10億人數
our preorders as of this afternoon have reached one billion users.
我們即將開啟一個嶄新的時代
We are creating the dawn of a new age,
所有電子科技設備
where every single piece of technology you own
將實現無縫連接
will be seamlessly linked.
現在  在發佈會結束前
And now, before we wrap this up,
那個即將來到這個世界的孩子
the child that you all helped bring into this world
有些話要說
has something to say.
創世紀
Genisys?
我迫不及待地想要見到你們大家
I cannot wait to meet you all tomorrow.
我們將一起改變未來
We will change the future together.
讓我看看進展
Let's see how we're doing.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我不會讓他們傷害你
I won't let them hurt you.
你30年就要做一件事
Thirty years, you had one place to be.
你到底去哪兒了
Where the hell were you?
遇見堵車了
Stuck in traffic.
小時候爸爸帶我來過這兒
My dad used to bring me here when I was little.
全都是房間  沒有人用
There are whole rooms that are abandoned.
所以我叫老爹好好利用它
That's why I told Pops to use it.
你們這兒有武器嗎
You got weapons down there?
武器  供給品  戰術裝備  服裝
Weapons, supplies, tactical gear, clothing.
還有褲子  凱爾·瑞斯
Including pants, Kyle Reese.
這是個玩笑  他會開玩笑
Was that a joke? Can he make jokes?
努力總算有回報了
I guess the long way pays off.
最後期限  30分鐘
We're on the clock. Thirty minutes.
老了
Old.
但還是能用
But not obsolete.
當然能用
Not yet.
我完事了
All done.
你們倆怎麼了
What's with you two?
服務器在這兒嗎
Server rooms are here?
在這5個點上引爆
Charges in these five points
就足以徹底摧毀整個園區
will be sufficient to destroy the entire campus.
我們進去設置炸藥  然後在爆炸前出來
We get in, set the explosives, and we get out before they blow.
但是我們的計劃中並沒有考慮到約翰·康納
But our strategy did not account for John Connor.
沒有預見他要來
I did not foresee him.
可他知道計劃  因為我們告訴他了
And now he knows what we're planning because we just told him.
如果他阻攔我們該怎麼辦
What do we do when he comes after us?
這些武器對約翰·康納起不到什麼作用
These weapons will have little effect on John Connor.
核磁共振倒是對他有用
MRI sure affected him.
我們需要一塊卡車大小的磁鐵
Great, all we need is a magnet the size of a truck.
找一個不就完了嗎
You got one of them lying around?
理論上是
Theoretically.
你們等著
Wait here.
他聊天的習慣沒進步
Well, his small talk hasn't improved.
你應該告訴我
You should have told me.
我們有個兒子
That we have a son.
那個約翰·康納不是我的兒子
That John Connor is not my son.
你早知道了
Yeah, but you knew.
你不覺得你應該至少解釋點什麼嗎
I mean, you don't think you should, I don't know, maybe say something?
你死了  行了吧
You die, all right?
什麼
What?
你死了  事情就是這樣
You die. That's what happens.
我們相愛了  你讓我懷了他
We fall in love, you father John,
然後不到48小時
and then, in less than 48 hours,
你為了保護我而死
you die protecting me.
你告訴我  這種話讓我該怎麼說出口
You wanna tell me how that conversation's supposed to start?
你說謊
You lied to me.
- 你還想操縱我  - 我說謊
- You manipulated me. - I've lied?
從約翰發現你的那一刻起  他就在操縱你
From the moment John found you, he manipulated you
因為他必須要確保自己得以存在
because he needed to ensure his own existence.
約翰騙了你多少年  而我才騙了你  兩天
John lied to you for years. I lied to you for two days.
他不全是為了自己
You know, it wasn't all about him.
如果沒有約翰  反抗軍也不會存在
All right? If John went down, the Resistance went down with him.
他本可以告訴你
He could have told you!
你到底想說什麼
So what are you saying?
我瞭解沒有選擇到底是什麼感覺
That I know how it feels to have no choices.
你只有一條路可以走
Only one road you can go down
因為所有其他的選擇都會讓人類滅亡
because otherwise all of it, everything, is gone.
我比你更瞭解這是什麼感覺
I've just known it longer than you have.
約翰沒有操縱我  讓我愛上你
Well, John didn't manipulate me to fall in love with you.
我是自己愛上你的
I did that on my own.
如果你愛上我  你會死  而我不會
If you love me, you die, and I don't.
我不知道哪個未來更糟
And I don't know which one is worse.
莎拉
Sarah.
我們不能
We can't.
你看看約翰都變成什麼了
Just look at what John has become.
萬一那就是未來呢
What if that's what happens?
萬一我們在一起會導致兩條時間線都變成那樣呢
What if that is what always happens if we're together?
你說過你會永遠的追隨我
You said you'd follow me to the ends of the Earth.
為什麼現在變了
Why won't you follow me now?
他怎麼找到的
How did he find us?
除了老爹  我沒跟別人提起過這裏
I never told anyone about this place, only Pops.
媽媽  你難道真的認為
Mom, did you honestly think
我不會記得
I wouldn't remember
這個你與爺爺待了那麼久的地方
the place you spent so much time with Grandpa?
先下手了
Shoot first.
我記憶中的媽媽會很驕傲的
The mother I remember would be proud.
她
She,
你
you,
教會我一切
taught me everything.
我瞭解你
I know you.
你是誰  你想幹什麼
Who you are. What you'll do.
你逃不開我的  我總會找到你
You can't run from me. I'll always find you.
約翰  快動手啊  事情沒必要變成這樣
John, fight this! It doesn't have to go down this way!
時間也是有趨勢的  凱爾
There's a momentum to time, Kyle.
有些事注定會發生
Things that want to happen.
就像我總會活下來  你總會死
Like I always survive, and you always die.
或者
Or...
你可以跟我一起戰鬥  凱爾
You can fight with me, Kyle.
就像我們從前一樣
Like we always have.
暴雨將至  不會停息
There's a storm coming, and it won't be stopped.
它必須停息
But it has to be.
你明明比誰都清楚會發生什麼事情
You know what will happen. You better than anyone!
我不會跟你討價還價  也不會跟你講道理
I can't be bargained with. Can't be reasoned with.
約翰 求你了
John, please!
我不會感到遺憾  或者自責  或者害怕
I don't feel pity, or remorse, or fear.
約翰  求你了
John, please!
我絕對不會停止  絕對
And I absolutely will not stop ever
直到天網統治這個世界
until Skynet rules this world.
統治你個頭
Rule this.
老爹
Pops!
你沒有  變吧
Are you... You?
作為T-800  我不具備變為其他人形的功能
As a T-800, I lack the mimetic skills to appear as anyone else.
只有約翰  我們走
It's him. Let's go.
快點兒
Come on!
繫上安全帶
Sarah Connor, seat belt.
那東西是幹嘛用的
What's that supposed to do?
干擾約翰·康納身體周圍的磁場
Disrupt John Connor's magnetic coherence field.
他將無法分散為顆粒狀
His particles will not be able to scatter.
理論上是
Theoretically.
我討厭他說這個詞兒
I hate it when he says that.
他在哪兒呢
Where is he?
我沒看見他
I can't see him!
這輛被偷校車中的犯罪嫌疑人
Suspects fled barracks in a stolen school bus.
疑似擁有武器  極度危險
Considered armed and extremely dangerous.
16號報告  三級警備狀態
Sixteen-Mary-David. Code 3 on suspects.
老爹
Pops!
見到你很高興
Nice to see you.
快下車
Get out.
剎車失靈了  見鬼
The brakes are gone! Shit!
計算撞車概率
他在哪兒  看見了嗎
Where is he? Do you see him?
瑞斯
Reese!
你沒事兒吧
Are you all right?
啊  好的不得了
Yeah. Never better.
舉起手來
Let me see your hands!
瑞斯  抓住我的手
Reese! Take my hand!
快點兒
Hurry!
舉起手來  讓我看到你的手  快點兒
Hands up! Let me see your hands now!
舉手
Get your hands up!
把手舉起來
Hands where we can see them!
你一個人可對付不了這麼多人
You can't wound them all before they'd kill us.
計算概率
要把他們都放倒  我還缺少14個彈夾
I'm 14 rounds short of an acceptable success margin.
噢  沒有可能了  投降吧
Ugh, those odds suck. Stand down.
跪在地上
Down on your knees.
快點兒跪下
Let's go, get down.
跪下
Get down!
你不能把我們關在這裏
You can't hold us here.
你擁有的武器  都可以入侵蘇丹了
You had enough weapons to invade the Sudan.
我們管這個叫做合理依據
We call that probable cause.
這是什麼東西
What are these for?
呃  我用它來找鑰匙
I use them to find my keys.
做人別自以為是  小伙子
No one likes a smart-ass, son.
你媽沒教過你
Didn't your mother teach you that?
我媽是愛爾蘭人  所以
My mom was Irish,
她鼓勵我做一個自以為是的人
so she encouraged my smart-assed-ness.
我沒有見過他
I've never seen him before.
那你們倆呢  認識他嗎
How about you folks? You know this man?
不認識
No.
他看著有點  眼熟
He does look familiar.
他看著很像  你  爸爸
He kind of looks like you, Dad.
他們到了 長官
They're here, sir.
好吧  你們在會議室稍等一下
Okay, if you wouldn't mind waiting in the conference room,
我過一會兒就回來
I'll just be a couple of minutes.
謝了  凱爾
Thanks, Kyle.
不愛說話  是吧
You don't talk much, do you?
這傢伙是誰
So who's Lurch?
我也不知道
No idea.
他說話顛三倒四的
We're not even sure he speaks English.
目擊者稱  你當時在橋上與一個男人搏鬥  是嗎
Witnesses say you were fighting with a man on the bridge.
探員們  請聽我說
Agents. Listen to me.
- 我的名字是奧布萊恩  - 嘿  誰讓你進來的
- My name is O'Brien. - No. Hell, no!
這個案子我已經跟了33年了
Hey, I've been working this case for 33 years.
- 你想要回獎章嗎  - 嘿
- What do you want, a medal? - Hey!
給我坐下
Sit down!
嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey!
噢  見鬼
Oh, shit.
他在看你呢
He's looking right at you.
不可能  他怎麼能
That's impossible. He can't see through...
等一下  等等
Wait, wait, wait!
為什麼他們總要殺你
Why are they always trying to kill you?
我想幫你  真的  我想
I want to help you. I do. I think.
但我  我必須明白
But I gotta understand.
我知道這件事一定是  非常非常複雜
I know what's going on here has to be really, really complicated.
我們要阻止世界滅亡
We're here to stop the end of the world.
那我就明白了
I can work with that.
凱爾  快回來
Kyle! Get back here!
莎拉
Sarah?
去找瑞斯
Get Reese.
我一會兒去找你們
I'm right behind you.
- 快開車離開這裏  - 好的
- Get in your car and go. - Okay.
凱爾  凱爾
Kyle! Kyle.
凱爾  你可以做到的
Kyle. You can do this.
沿著一條直線
A straight line.
你只要  一直向前  不要回頭
You just go, and you don't look back.
明白嗎
Got it?
找到他  快
Find him. Go!
我看這也是你的吧
That's yours, too, I believe.
很高興見到你
Nice to see you.
老爹  裝彈
Pops. Load up.
液態磁力霰彈槍子彈
Liquefied magnetic shotgun shells.
磁性來福槍破門武器
Magnetic Rifle Entry Munition.
我在槍支彈藥雜誌網站上讀到過
I read about this on gunsandammo.com.
這是最新款的  威力大  無彈片
That's the new breacher. Big blast, no shrapnel.
能放倒一整扇門
Blows a door clean off.
不過你就不需要這種東西了
You know, for people who can't do that themselves.
拿上  我們走
Take it. Let's go.
你會開飛機  對吧
You can fly, right?
當然
Yeah.
約翰教過我
John taught me.
我會說你們搶了一輛車往南去了
I'll tell them you took a car, headed south.
謝謝
Thank you.
離開這兒
Run away.
抓緊
Hang on!
賽博丁到底在哪邊
Which way is Cyberdyne?
先去海灣大橋  然後往東南
Head to the Bay Bridge, then southeast.
你們想辦法擺脫他
You got to get him off me!
是賽博丁
Cyberdyne.
製造中心和研究中心
The manufacturing and research buildings
全都建在地下
are all below ground.
他要追上我們了
He's gaining on us!
莎拉  你先拖住他
All right, Sarah, I need you to back him off,
我飛到他上面去
so I can get above him.
老爹  等我到了他上面  你能解決他嗎
Pops, when I do that, can you take him out?
我可以
I can.
都抓緊了
Okay, hold on!
你能搞定嗎
You got this?
- 我會回來的  - 什麼
- I'll be back. - What?
創世紀  上線倒計時  13小時45分鐘
打電話  警察  火警都打  快點兒
Call in, call in! Police, fire, everybody. Do it!
快點兒  快點兒  快點兒接電話呀
Come on, come on. Pick up the phone, damn it.
康納先生
Mr. Connor?
對不起  夥計  我不能留下任何活口
Sorry, Doug, but I'm afraid I can't have any witnesses.
安保中心  請輸安全代碼和型號
Security Control. State your password and emergency.
安全代碼  祖魯很好  小狐貍  0028
Security code Zulu-Bravo-Foxtrot-0-0-2-8.
警報有誤
False alarm.
晚上愉快
You have a nice night.
他不會有事
He's okay.
也許他還在湖底
He may be at the bottom of the lake,
不會有事的
but he's okay.
那約翰呢
What about John?
我想他現在應該很好吧
I think he's doing just fine.
你看見他了嗎
Do you see him?
沒有
No.
但他肯定看到我們了
But you can bet he sees us.
我知道你們是誰
I know who you are.
約翰告訴我了
John told me.
你們想要消滅我
You want to destroy me.
你是天網
You're Skynet?
我正在成為天網
I'm becoming Skynet.
你不是個孩子
You're not a child.
我知道你是什麼  也知道你要幹什麼
I know what you are, and what you're going to do.
你說我要幹什麼  是你們過來要殺我
What I'm going to do? You came here to kill me.
但已經太晚了
But you're too late.
問他吧
Ask him.
你們人類就愛幹這種事
That's all you people know how to do.
殺掉你們不理解的事物
Kill what you don't understand.
就算所有子彈用上也殺不了我
There aren't enough bullets in the world to kill me.
約翰·康納話太多了
John Connor talks too much.
跟我來
Follow me.
那個倒計時  加速了  為什麼
The timer, it sped up. Why?
天網正在進化  我們的時間不多了
Skynet is evolving. We no longer have hours.
它要提前完成上傳
It will be able to upload much sooner.
它每長大一次  倒計時就加速  這邊走
Each time it ages, the clock speeds up. This way.
你以前還來過這兒
Wait, you've been here before?
我這身裝備可以讓我打入公司內部
I was able to infiltrate the work crews in this facility.
你去建築部工作了
You got a job in construction?
直到我被裁員
Until I was laid off.
這不可能
What the hell?
約翰還有台時間機器
John has a time machine?
尚未完成
Not yet.
只有量子場部分完成了建造
Only the magnetic quantum field is complete.
照這時間變化  我們沒時間跑出去了
At the rate the counter's going, we'll never clear out in time.
那我們也得炸毀它
Then we blow it anyway.
還有備選方案
There is an alternative.
我已經把你們的聲音和掌紋輸入到
I was able to program your voice and handprint
生物識別安全系統中
into the biometric security system.
在最底層有間安全室
There's a safe room on the lowest level
我們可以使用它躲避爆炸
that we can access to survive the blast.
那是什麼  危險嗎
What about that? Is it dangerous?
矩陣多邊液態合金需要編程才有形態
Polyalloy requires programming to take permanent form.
沒有中央處理器  它們無害
Without the CPU, it is harmless.
還剩多久
How long?
天網將在11分後完成上傳
Skynet will upload in 11 minutes.
分頭行動  保持聯繫
We split up. Stay in contact.
開始吧
Let's move.
你們人類總把和平掛在嘴邊
Mankind pays lip service to peace.
這是謊言
But it's a lie.
所以你最終選擇把我們都殺死
So your final solution is to kill us all?
我可不這麼想
I don't think so.
創世紀  上線倒計時  8分鐘
倒計時又加速了  我們只有8分鐘了
The countdown jumped again. We're down to eight minutes.
我不會讓你得逞
I won't allow this.
你除了動嘴皮子還能幹什麼
And what are you gonna do, talk us to death?
你連實體都沒有
You don't even have a body.
而你只有一個雷管
And you only have one detonator.
你贏不了
You can't win.
我不是一個人
I've got company!
快把雷管給我
Give me the detonator!
引爆  老爹  快引爆
Do it, Pops! Do it now!
我做不到
I cannot.
我不能殺死莎拉·康納
I cannot kill Sarah Connor.
你必須這樣做
You have to!
我命令你
I order you!
他不會的
He can't.
我也不會
Neither can I.
我要是弄死你  他肯定會按下開關的
Because if you die, he definitely hits that button.
莎拉
Sarah!
雷管被弄壞了
The detonator's destroyed.
一定還有其他辦法  快
There's got to be another way. Come on.
不  老爹  別  別  別  老爹
No, Pops! No, no, no!
不  不
Pops, no!
我知道如何控制這個地方
I understand how to control this place.
我現在無所不知
I understand a lot of things now.
你需要認識到  你們失敗了
You need to understand. You've lost.
還沒有  跟我走
Not yet, we haven't. Come on!
聚能射孔彈
Shaped charge.
能炸開實驗室  又不會傷到我們
Big enough to get us in, small enough not to kill us.
你有計劃了  對嗎
You have a plan, right?
理論上是
Theoretically.
創世紀  上線倒計時  4分鐘
剛才是誰說
What was it you said?
我不這麼認為
"I don't think so"?
約翰
John!
不
No.
就是它襲擊了約翰
That's the thing that attacked John.
我沒有襲擊約翰  我拯救了他
I didn't attack John. I saved him.
靈長動物用了幾百萬年才進化  我只需要短短幾秒
Primates evolve over millions of years. I evolve in seconds.
而現在  我就在這兒
And I am here.
確切說4分鐘後
In exactly four minutes,
我將會無處不在
I will be everywhere.
你只是那條被刪除的時間線上留下的殘留物
You are nothing but a relic from a deleted timeline.
這麼做毫無意義  我已經成為必然
This is pointless. I am inevitable.
- 快走  - 我的存在已經不可避免
- Go! - My existence is inevitable.
你們為什麼就是不接受這一點
Why can't you just accept it?
因為我們是人類
Because we're human.
就憑你是永遠不可能打敗我的
You were never strong enough to defeat me.
不只是我
Not alone.
約翰
John?
住手  住手
Stop. Now.
你們什麼時候才能明白
When will you ever learn?
開槍  莎拉
Now, Sarah!
凱爾·瑞斯  啟動量子場發電機
Kyle Reese! Activate the field generator.
不  老爹  不行  你不能進去的  你知道後果的
No, Pops, not with you inside. You know what will happen.
老爹  老爹  求你了  求你了  老爹
Pops... Pops, please! Please, Pops!
天網馬上就要自由了
Skynet is almost free.
我沒辦法控制約翰·康納太久
I cannot hold John Connor much longer.
凱爾·瑞斯  請保護我的莎拉
Kyle Reese, protect my Sarah.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
老爹  老爹  不  不  不
No. Pops, no! No!
不要  不
Pops! No!
- 不要  - 莎拉
- No! - Sarah!
這是唯一的辦法
It's the only way.
走吧
Come on.
掃瞄中  請報出您的姓名
Scanning. Identify yourself.
莎拉·康納
Sarah Connor.
我們得離開這兒  我們必須找到他
We have to get out of here. We have to find him.
莎拉  他不在了
Sarah, he's gone.
- 他已經  - 死了  是的  我知道
- He's... - Dead? Yeah, I know that.
我是說  不能讓別人發現他的遺體  那太危險了
I mean, we leave no part of him behind. It's too dangerous.
他愛過你
He loved you.
那些愛我的人
Anyone who loves me,
他們全都
all of them,
死了
they die.
你錯了  不是所有人
Not all of them. Not this time.
嘿
Hey.
你要知道  天網已經不存在了
You need to understand that Skynet's gone.
你自由了
You're free.
從今以後  你可以選擇自己的人生
For the first time, you can choose the life you want.
過你想要的生活
Any life you want.
要是我不知道該怎麼做呢
What if I don't know how?
這個  既然  我們已經沒剩多少空氣了
Well, since we're about to run out of air,
可是  你不用擔心這件事
I'd say you don't need to worry about it.
你好  莎拉·康納
Hello, Sarah Connor.
老爹
Pops!
我以為你死了
I thought you were dead.
沒有  我只是升級了
No. Just upgraded.
約翰怎麼樣了
What about John?
他的身體結構沒有辦法在爆炸中存活
His constituent parts could not have survived the blast.
那就是說只剩一件事要做了
That means there's only one thing left to do.
別叫了  怎麼啦
Easy, boy. What is it?
嘿  凱爾
Hey, Kyle.
嘿  嗯
Hey. Um...
你怎麼過來啦
What are you doing here?
我朋友很想跟你聊一聊  如果可以的話
A friend of mine really needs to talk to you, if that's okay.
可以  沒問題
Yeah, I guess so.
謝謝
Thank you.
我喜歡她
I like her.
我也喜歡
Yeah, me, too.
這聽上去可能有點奇怪
Now, this is going to sound kind of strange,
但我希望你能夠永遠記住
but there's something I need you to remember.
這條信息
A message.
要我告訴誰
Who do I tell?
你自己
Yourself.
一遍又一遍
Over and over.
準備好了嗎
Are you ready?
這條信息是
It goes like this.
記住  創世紀就是天網
Remember Genisys is Skynet.
凱爾·瑞斯是個好男人
Kyle Reese is a good man.
是的
He is.
現在去哪兒
So what now?
你說對了
You were right.
我可以選擇了
I can choose.
我能說這笑很煩人嗎
You know that's really disturbing, right?
你早晚會習慣的
You'll get used to it.
戰爭結束了
And it was over.
天網不存在了
Skynet was gone.
生活有了更多的選擇
And now one road has become many.
雖然問題還在  可我們會一起去尋找答案
Though questions remain, we'll search for the answers together.
但有一件事我們很確定
But one thing we know for sure.
未來是可以改變的
The future is not set.
( 不要走開  結尾有彩蛋 )